Yongwei Chen | Curriculum Vitae

 \square +86 155-2122-5171 \diamond \heartsuit Singapore ✓ yongwei001@e.ntu.edu.sg ♦ ♦ cyw-3d.github.io

Computer Vision | 3D Vision | Multimodal Learning | Graphics

OVERVIEW

I am currently conducting my research and will pursue my PhD studies in MMLab@NTU, supervised by Xingang Pan. Prior to this, I earned both my Master's and Bachelor's degrees at South China University of Technology, under the mentorship of Kui Jia. My primary research interest lies in the exciting and constantly-evolving realm of 3D vision and graphics, with a particular emphasis on 3D generation.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree

School of Electronic and Information Engineering

GPA: 3.92/4.00, rank 3/242

Master's Degree

Information and Communication Engineering

Advisor: Prof. Kui Jia

South China University of Technology

2016.09 - 2020.06

South China University of Technology

2020.09 - 2023.12

RECENT PUBLICATION

- [1] Y. Chen*, T. Wang*, T. Wu, X. Pan, K. Jia and Z. Liu, "ComboVerse: Compositional 3D Assets Creation Using Spatially-Aware Diffusion Guidance.", in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2024.
- R. Chen*, Y. Chen*, N. Jiao and K. Jia, "Fantasia3D: Disentangling Geometry and Appearance for High-quality Text-to-3D Content Creation.", in International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2023.
- Y. Chen, R. Chen, J. Lei, Y. Zhang and K. Jia, "TANGO: Text-driven Photorealistic and Robust 3D Stylization via Lighting Decomposition.", in Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022. spotlight
- [4] Y. Chen*, Z. Wang*, L. Zou, K. Chen, and K. Jia, "Quasi-Balanced Self-Training on Noise-Aware Synthesis of Object Point Clouds for Closing Domain Gap.", in European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV),
- [5] M. Yang, Y. Wen, W. Chen, Y. Chen, and K. Jia, "Deep Optimized Priors for 3D Shape Modeling and Reconstruction.", in IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Intern

2021.11 - 2023.09

Dexforce, Shenzhen

Research Intern Shanghai AI Laboratory, Shanghai

2023.09 - 2024.01

SKILLS

Proficient: Python (Pytorch), Blender, LATEX

Familiar: C++, CUDA

AWARDS

Samsung Scholarship, South China University of Technology

2018.03

National Scholarship, South China University of Technology

2018.11

National Scholarship, South China University of Technology

2019.12